http://www.kilgore.edu/about/website-privacy-policy

Jump to navigation
You are hereAbout / Website Privacy Policy
Website Privacy Policy
Also, view copyright information
Privacy Policy:
Kilgore College maintains the KC website (www.kilgore.edu) as a public service. The following statement applies only to members of the general public and is intended to address concerns about the types of information gathered from the public, if any, and how that information is used.
NOTE: The Kilgore College website is provided as a public service and information source to our students, faculty and staff and the community. Official policies and procedures of the institution are published in the College Catalog, the Board Procedures Manual, and the Student Handbook. Should there be any discrepancies between the website and any of these documents, the catalog, handbook and/or policy manual shall take precedence.
I. Notice of Personal Information
The following notice is provided in accordance with Section 559.003(a) of the Texas Government Code:
With few exceptions, you are entitled on your request to be informed about the information Kilgore College collects about you; Under Sections 552.021 and 552.023 of the Texas Government Code, you are entitled to receive and review the information; and Under Section 559.004 of the Texas Government Code, you are entitled to have Kilgore College correct information about you that is held by Kilgore College and is incorrect.
The information that Kilgore College collects will be retained and maintained as required by Texas records retention laws (Section 441.180 et. Seq. of the Texas Government Code) and rules. Different types of information are kept for different periods of time.
II. Cookies
A "cookie" is a small file containing information that is placed on a user's computer by a web server. Typically, these files are used to enhance the user's experience of the site, to help users move between pages in a database, or to customize information for a user.
Any information that Kilgore College webservers may store in cookies is used for internal purposes only. Cookie data is not used in any way that would disclose personally identifiable information to outside parties unless Kilgore College is legally required to do so in connection with law enforcement investigations or other legal proceedings.
III. Logs and Network Monitoring
Kilgore College maintains log files of all access to its site and also monitors network traffic for the purposes of site management. This information is used to help diagnose problems with the server and to carry out other administrative tasks. Log analysis tools are also used to create summary statistics to determine which information is of most interest to users, to identify system problem areas, or to help determine technical requirements.
Information such as the following is collected in these files:
Hostname: the hostname and/or IP address of the computer requesting access to the site
User-Agent: the type of browser, its version, and the operating system of the computer requesting access.
Referer: the web page the user came from
System date: the date and time on the server at the time of access
Full request: the exact request the user made
Status: the status code the server returned, e.g., fullfilled request, file not found
Content length: the size, in bytes, of the file sent to the user
Method: the request method used by the browser (e.g., post, get)
Universal Resource Identifier (URI): the location of the particular resource requested.  (More commonly known as a URL.)
Query string of the URI: anything after a question mark in a URI.  For example, if a keyword search has been requested, the search word will appear in the query string.
Protocol: the technical protocol and version used, i.e., http 1.0, ftp, etc.
The above information is not used in any way that would reveal personally identifying information to outside parties unless System Administration is legally required to do so in connection with law enforcement investigations or other legal proceedings.
IV. E-mail and Form Information
If a member of the general public sends Kilgore College an e-mail message or fills out a web-based form with a question or comment that contains personally identifying information, that information will only be used to respond to the request and analyze trends. The message may be redirected to another government agency or person who is better able to answer your question. Such information is not used in any way that would reveal personally identifying information to outside parties unless Kilgore College is legally required to do so in connection with law enforcement investigations or other legal proceedings.
V. Links
This site contains links to other sites outside of Kilgore College. Kilgore College is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.
VI. Security
This site has security measures in place to protect from loss, misuse and alteration of the information under control of Kilgore College.
Contacting the Webmaster:
If there are any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or dealings with this website, contact the webmaster.
Facebook
Twitter
Print HTML
Forward
Favorite
Student Services
Career Services
Counseling/Advising
Strategic Plan
MenuAcademicsAcademicsBackAdult Education and LiteracyAdult Education and LiteracyBackLearn about AEL at KC
Distance Learning (AEL)
English as a Second Language (ESL)
Exam Preparation
Integrated Education and Training (IET)
Intensive College Readiness Program
TxCHSE Preparation and Testing
All Choices A-Z
Available Courses Search
Career PathwaysCareer PathwaysBackCareer Pathways Home
Education, Human & Protective Services
Health Sciences
Information Technology, Business & Personal Services
Liberal & Fine Arts
Manufacturing, Transportation & Industrial Technology
Science, Technology, Engineering & Mathematics
Calendar (Campus Events Calendar)
Classes Listed by DivisionClasses Listed by DivisionBackArts & Mathematical SciencesArts & Mathematical SciencesBackAdvertising and Graphic Design Technology
Art
Communications and Journalism
Education and College Success
Engineering
English
Geography
Government
History
Theatre (Drama)
Business & Computer ScienceBusiness & Computer ScienceBackBarber Program
BusinessBusinessBackBusiness (Transfer)
Accounting
Business Management
Business Computer Office Management
CosmetologyCosmetologyBackCosmetology - Operator Certificate
Public Services & Industrial TechnologiesPublic Services & Industrial TechnologiesBackAutomotive Technology
Heating, Ventilation, Air Conditioning & Refrigeration Technology
Science & Health SciencesScience & Health SciencesBackAthletic Training
Medical (Pre-Professional)
Nursing (RN, LVN to RN)
Nurse Assistant (Aide)
College CatalogsCollege CatalogsBackCollege Catalog (2020-21)
College Catalog (2019-20)
College Catalog (2018-19)
College Catalog (2017-18)
Course Evaluation Results
Course Syllabi - HB 2504
December Mini Courses
Dual Credit for High School StudentsDual Credit for High School StudentsBackLearn about Dual Credit at KC
Online Classes (eLearning)
Police Academy
University Transfer
Community Education and Lifelong Learning CoursesCommunity Education and Lifelong Learning CoursesBackCE-Lifelong Learning Homepage
Community Education Classes Offered in HendersonCommunity Education Classes Offered in HendersonBackBusiness Leadership Skills Certificate
Culinary Arts Community Education Non-Credit Course
Workforce EducationWorkforce EducationBackWorkforce Education Homepage
Business Leadership
Contract Training
Electric Power Technology
HR Specialist Certificate
Human Resource Courses (SHRM)
Transportation Institute (CDL)
Future StudentsFuture StudentsBackNew Students - Start HereNew Students - Start HereBackInformation for students new to KC
Payment OptionsPayment OptionsBackLearn about Payment Options at KC
Financial Aid Satisfactory Academic Progress (SAP)
Police Department (KCPD)
Registrar's Office
Student Success Programs
Summer Bridge Program
Testing ServicesTesting ServicesBackTesting Center in Kilgore
Calendar (Campus Events Calendar)
Career Services
CARES Act Info & Application
College Catalog & Student Handbook (2020-2021)
Payment OptionsPayment OptionsBackLearn about Payment Options at KC
Registration & TranscriptsRegistration & TranscriptsBackRegistrar's Office
Student Emergency Fund (T.L.L. Temple Foundation)
Student Emergency Fund
Student ServicesStudent ServicesBackBone Learning Center
Bookstore
Career Services
Counseling and Academic AdvisingCounseling and Academic AdvisingBackMental Health Resources in the Community
Police Department (KCPD)
Registrar's Office
Student Success Programs
Testing Services in KilgoreTesting Services in KilgoreBackComputer Competency Course
Testing Services in Longview
Tuition & Fees
Tutoring ServicesTutoring ServicesBackTutoring Lab - Longview-North Zone
Tutoring Lab - The Zone in Kilgore
TRIO Fast Track Program
Writing Studios
Tuition & Fees
Campus LifeCampus LifeBackCalendar (Campus Events Calendar)
Athletics & OrganizationsAthletics & OrganizationsBackOrganizationsOrganizationsBackAmbassadors
Athletic FacilitiesAthletic FacilitiesBackR.E. St. John Memorial Stadium
Calendar (Academic Calendar)
Calendar (Campus Events Calendar)
Copyright Information
CommunityCommunityBackCity of Kilgore
Kilgore Chamber of Commerce
Kilgore Economic Development Corp.
Faculty/Staff and BoardFaculty/Staff and BoardBackAdministration
Board of TrusteesBoard of TrusteesBackMay 2021 General Election
Institutional AdvancementInstitutional AdvancementBackKC Foundation
Institutional InformationInstitutional InformationBackAccreditation
KC Cares: Compliment or Concern?
KC Foundation
KC-Longview
Maps & LocationsMaps & LocationsBackKC Maps and Directions
Marketing Request
Offices & Services OfferedOffices & Services OfferedBackAdmissions and Registrar
Bookstore
Business Office
Career Services
Cashier's OfficeCashier's OfficeBackCollege Green Payment Plan
PAY NOW
eLearning (Online Classes)
Grants at KCGrants at KCBackGrants Manual
Title III
Housing Services
Human Resources
Information Technology (IT)Information Technology (IT)BackHelp Desk
Police Department (KCPD)Police Department (KCPD)BackKCPD Homepage
